Gilberto Ramirez | Software Engineer



gramirez.softwareengineer@gmail.com | 🐨 github.com/Gilberto-Felipe | 💇 LinkedIn: gilbertoramirez-swe





Summary

I'm a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in full-stack positions. I have experience in the development of Content Management Systems and ERP applications. I'm applying for a backend position for Autonomous Vehicles. I am keenly interested in developing a career in autonomous driving and connected cars. Open to remote positions o relocation in Sweden.

Main skills: .NET Core C#, SQL Server/MySQL, React.

Experience

Full-stack Engineer | DPR Construction | 2021 - present [2 year] | Remote

C#, Web APIs with .Net Core and Entity Framework, SQL Server, Git, Javascript/ES6, React, Reactstrap, Material UI (MUI), Formik, Chrome DevTools, ActiveBatch

- Human Resource Planning Management System: Developed and did maintenance for 30 modules. This application is used by 50+ HR.
- Management System for SMS: Developed generic components and the modules for watching the pending SMS, and SMS sent. We developed the first version in 6 months.
- Asset Management System: The system keep tracks of the asset leasing. Developed 8 modules and did mentorship to a new colleague.
- Coordinated the migration of 409 plans/jobs from different technologies to ActiveBatch. The effort lasted 9 months and involved 7 engineers from different teams.

Full-stack Web Developer | GHAPPS | 2019 - 2020 [1 year 8 months] | Colima, Mexico

PHP, MySQL, Git, HTML5, CSS, Javascript/ES6, JQuery, Bootstrap, AdminLTE

• Collaborated in the development of a Content Management System. It provides information for Loro Fan, the mobile app of the University of Colima soccer team. Developed the database, the login, UI views, and the backend. The app has 100 downloads for Android.

Education

Bachelor degree in Software Engineering | University of Colima | 2017-2021 | Colima, Mexico C# Courses | Plural Sight | 2021 | Online: Beginning Collections, Building an API with ASP.NET Core. Python for Everybody Specialization | Coursera | 2020 | Online Bachelor degree in Philosophy | Regina Apostolorum | 2007-2011 | Rome, Italy